A Finding Aid to the W.G. Constable Papers, 1905-1983, bulk 1920-1976, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Research Files, 1922-1976; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 7.5 Linear feet Box 16-24, OV 28-29
  - Schools of Art, circa 1940-1960; 8.9; Archival Resource Key
    - English (site specific objects, A-S), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - English (site specific objects, T), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - English (site specific objects, U-Z), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - English (watercolors), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - English (watercolors), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - English (watercolors), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - English (miscellaneous), circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Spanish, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Flemish, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - French, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - German, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - German, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Italian, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Italian, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Italian, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Scandinavian, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Scandinavian, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Craft, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Iconography, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Illuminated Manuscripts, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Sculpture, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Oversize Diagram, English (14th-19th century) scanned with Box 23, Folder 29, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Pamphlet, Miscellaneous Illuminated Manuscripts scanned with Box 24, Folder 16, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Printed Material, English (14th-19th century) scanned with Box 23, Folder 32, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 29)
- Printed Material, 1921-1977; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 24
  Printed materials include clippings on Constable's work as a museum curator and art historian, as well as articles on miscellaneous art topics; programs; book excerpts and other miscellaneous printed materials.
  - Book Excerpt, [Engravings], 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Book Excerpt, [Miniatures], circa 1920-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Book Excerpt, Ninth Volume of the Walpole Society, 1920-1921, Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, Biographical, circa 1925-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1925-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1938-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1951-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1962-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, General Reference, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, General Reference, circa 1930-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, General Reference, 1927-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, General Reference, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, General Reference, 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Programs, circa 1920-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Programs, 1924-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Programs, 1940-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Programs, 1951-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1930-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1934-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 44)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1940-1960; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Box 24-27, OV 28-29
  Photographic materials include prints of Constable with friends and family. There are also prints, glass negatives and slides of paintings, sculpture and architectural buildings. Photographs and negatives of artwork are assumed to be for research purposes. The series also includes prints of the Fogg Art Museum's interiors and exterior and interior shots of Tennessee Valley Authority dam projects.
  Materials are arranged by document and subject type.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned, including glass plate negatives. Duplicates, and blank versos of photographs have not been scanned.
  - Photographs of W.G. Constable, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of W.G. Constable and Friends, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of W.G. Constable with Works of Art, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - Photographs of Fogg Art Museum, Interiors, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of Fogg Art Museum, Interiors, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) Dams, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Negatives of Artwork Reproduced from Nitrate Film, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Artwork and Architecture, Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, A-G, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, H-K, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, L, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, M, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, N-S, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, T, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, U-Z, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Artwork for Consideration, Unidentified, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 8.
  - Glass Negatives of Artwork, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 26)
    23 glass plate negatives
  - Original Boxes for Glass Negatives, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Original Boxes for Glass Negatives, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Architecture, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Architecture, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Architecture, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Glass Slides of Artwork, Sculpture, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Oversize Photographs, Artwork for Consideration, Unidentified scanned with Box 25, Folder 12, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 8)